<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Dominik Grzelak</title><link>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on Dominik Grzelak</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2024, Dr.-Ing. Dominik Grzelak</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Successfully Completed My Doctoral Procedure</title><link>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/successfully-completed-my-doctoral-procedure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/successfully-completed-my-doctoral-procedure/</guid><description>I am excited to announce that I have successfully completed my doctoral procedure at the Faculty of Computer Science at the University of Technology Dresden, Germany. After a challenging and rewarding journey, I have officially received my doctoral certificate.
Thesis Title: &amp;ldquo;Model-oriented Programming with Bigraphical Reactive Systems: Theory and Implementation&amp;rdquo; Date of Defense: December 15, 2023 A heartfelt thank you to everyone who supported me along the way!</description></item><item><title>Joining University of Technology Dresden as a Research Associate in CeTI</title><link>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/joining-tu-dresden-research-associate-ceti/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/joining-tu-dresden-research-associate-ceti/</guid><description>After the completion of the EU IoSense Project, I applied for a full-time position as a Research Associate at the Centre for Tactile Internet with Human-in-the-Loop (CeTI) – a Cluster of Excellence at the University of Technology Dresden, Germany. CeTI is dedicated to enabling seamless interaction between humans and cyber-physical systems in both real and virtual environments through intelligent communication networks and systems, all in near real-time.
In this role, I will focus on the theoretical building blocks for advancing robotic software by developing context-aware and domain-specific languages that enhance multimodal feedback and streamline programming for specific tasks and environments.</description></item><item><title>Joining University of Technology Dresden as a Research Associate in IoSense</title><link>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/joining-tu-dresden-research-associate-iosense/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/joining-tu-dresden-research-associate-iosense/</guid><description>I have applied for a full-time position as a Research Associate for the EU ECSEL IoSense Project at the University of Technology Dresden, Germany. IoSense is to enable flexible FE/BE sensor pilot lines for the Internet of Everything.</description></item><item><title>My Last Day at Symate GmbH</title><link>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/my-final-day-symate-gmbh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/my-final-day-symate-gmbh/</guid><description>After more than four years at Symate GmbH, I am moving on to new opportunities. I am grateful for everything I have learned during my time there.
While industry projects can be quite challenging, they are immensely rewarding and fulfilling upon successful completion, offering invaluable real-world experience.
I will always value the camaraderie and humor shared with my teammates and managers.
I had the privilege of making good friends with whom I remain in contact.</description></item><item><title>Joining University of Technology Chemnitz as a Research Associate in MERGE</title><link>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/joining-tu-chemnitz-research-associate-merge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/joining-tu-chemnitz-research-associate-merge/</guid><description>I have applied for a part-time position as a Research Associate for MERGE, a Cluster of Excellence at the University of Technology Chemnitz, Germany. MERGE focuses on enabling technologies for multifunctional lightweight structures.
My involvement is specifically within the Interacting Research Domain B, which concentrates on metal-intensive technologies, where I am part of the subproject IRD B4. This subproject is dedicated to evaluate the developed resource-efficient processes for producing hybrid lightweight structures.</description></item><item><title>Milestone Achieved: Completed My Master's Degree</title><link>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/milestone-achieved-completed-my-masters-degree/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/milestone-achieved-completed-my-masters-degree/</guid><description>Proud to announce I’ve completed my Master’s degrees at the Faculty of Engineering and Computer Science at the Brandenburgische Technische Universität Cottbus - Senftenberg.
Master Thesis (2014): &amp;ldquo;Automatische Klassifikation von Einrichtungsgegenständen, Landmarken und Hindernissen für blinde Fußgänger in Innenräumen&amp;rdquo; This work was conducted in collaboration with the Chair of Human-Computer Interaction at University of Technology Dresden. I am grateful for the support and encouragement from my professors, friends, and family, which motivated me throughout this journey.</description></item><item><title>Joining Symate GmbH as a Software Developer</title><link>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/joining-symate-gmbh-software-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/joining-symate-gmbh-software-developer/</guid><description>While completing my Master’s thesis, I applied for a part-time position at Symate GmbH as a Software Developer.
I am pleased to have been offered a permanent contract, and I am eagerly anticipating the new challenges ahead. My work will focus on real-world projects involving process modeling and sensor data analysis of assembly lines and machine processes, and will include collaboration with several industry partners.</description></item><item><title>My First Paper and Introduction to AI</title><link>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/first-conference-and-introduction-to-ai/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/first-conference-and-introduction-to-ai/</guid><description>I published my first paper for &amp;ldquo;Informatiktage 2012&amp;rdquo; at the B-IT Bonn-Aachen Center for Information Technology, which is a computer science congress organized by the Gesellschaft für Informatik e.V. (GI). I submitted an abstract on the topic of my Bachelor’s thesis and participated in both the poster session and the workshop held from March 23 to March 24, 2012.
It was a great pleasure to meet so many brilliant personalities. Early on, I was introduced to the concept of the Internet of Things and the transformative impact of AI on our future.</description></item><item><title>Milestone Achieved: Completed My Bachelor's Degree</title><link>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/milestone-achieved-completed-my-bachelors-degree/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dominikgrzelak.de/news/milestone-achieved-completed-my-bachelors-degree/</guid><description>I am pleased to announce that I have officially completed my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree at Hochschule Lausitz (FH) – University of Applied Sciences.
Bachelor Thesis (2011): &amp;ldquo;Automatisierte Erkennung von Influencern im Social Web&amp;rdquo; My research was complemented by a six-month internship at IBM Deutschland Research &amp;amp; Development GmbH in Böblingen, Germany, from March 15 to September 30, 2011. During this time, I gained valuable insights into large-scale computing infrastructures and the application of big data analysis on social media networks.</description></item></channel></rss>